<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "${ent.filename}">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter id="notes">
	<title>Important Notes</title>
   <!-- <section id="jss7_overview">
    	<title>Overview</title>-->
	<section id="notes_download">
		<title>Download</title>
		<para>
		The binary release is available for download from the TeleStax Customer Support Portal at <ulink url="&THIS.RELEASE_BINARY_URL;" />.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="notes_whats_included">
		<title>What's Included?</title>
		<para>
		This binary release includes: 
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>docs: Contains all relevant documentation.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>jboss-5.1.0.GA: The core server with two profiles "default" and "simulator". The "default" profile is a clean profile where you will have to start from scratch and configure the entire SS7 Stack and GMLC Gateway. The "simulator" profile is a pre-configured profile to work with jss7-simulator.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>resources: Contains SLEE MAP, JDBC, http-client, http-servlet and SIP RA jars.</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>tools: Contains SLEE tools and jss7-simulator.</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="Config_settings">
		<title>Configuration Settings</title>
		<para>You must perform post-installation configuration of the Gateway according to instructions in the &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; Admin Guide. Before using in Production, you must remember to fine-tune Memory, Database and logging settings for better performance. </para>
<warning><para>Failure to configure memory, database, logging and other settings as per the instructions in the Admin Guide may result in poor performance of the Gateway.</para></warning>
	</section>
	<section id="notes_doc">
		<title>Documentation</title>
		<para>
		When you download the binary release and extract the contents of the zip file, you will notice that the top level directory is named <literal>restcomm-gmlc-&lt;version&gt;</literal> and within the <literal>restcomm-gmlc-&lt;version&gt;/docs</literal> folder you will find the &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; Installation Guide and User Guide. For installation and usage guidance, please refer to these guides that will help you to install and configure the Gateway.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="notes_support">
		<title>Support</title>
		<para>
			&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; &THIS.VERSION; is fully supported by TeleStax. For help with the software or to raise bugs please login to your account at <ulink url="https://telestax.zendesk.com/home" /> and follow the instructions.
		</para>
	</section>
	
<!--	<section id="notes_whats_new">
		<title>What's New?</title>
		<para>
		This release is packed with important features, major fixes and performance improvements.
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para></para></listitem>
			<listitem><para></para></listitem>
			<listitem><para></para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
-->

		
</chapter>
